TAJAMAL HUSSAIN

+61 451 66 2064 tajamal.azan@gmail.com U 17/51 Olsen Avenue, QLD 4215, Australia.

Personal Summary:

Web developer with 07 years' experience in full stack hand code experience in Web and Mobile Applications development using an array of technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Redux, CLI, PHP. Experience with using Library of JavaScript such as React JS to create Single Page Application. Expertise in Bootstrap framework and building responsive website for different devices, such as desktop, laptop, mobile and iPad. Expert knowledge of the UI design process and deliverables throughout the development lifecycle. Strong knowledge of object oriented JavaScript programming. Also have experience in WordPress, Joomla, Shopify and developed the websites using PHP coding and developed custom themes, plugins and components.

Work Experience:

Web Developer at Avanti Project Marketing, Gold Coast QLD, Australia (Oct 2022 - Present)

- Developed official website of Avanti Project Marketing in WordPress (CMS).
- Collaborate with project management, digital marketing, and design on creating responsive and mobile-ready website using established techniques in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and PHP.
- Involve in requirements and analysis: Understanding the requirements of the client and the flow of the application as well as the application framework.
- Designed and developed the WordPress platform architecture.
- Worked with marketing teams to improve the existing user experience.

Senior Web Developer at Tkxel (Jan 2018 – June 2022)

- Worked as Web developer and involved in the analysis of requirements, the design, development, integration, deployment and testing.
- Previously I was working with HTML, PHP, JavaScript and CSS, Of course WordPress involves all those languages, now I specialize in custom WordPress.
- E-commerce web designs, SEO, online marketing/advertising, and social media marketing.
- Maintain an internal web application built on react/Angular Js, express, MongoDB and node. Js that
 automates quality and provide quality checks for internal and external websites leading to a reduction
 in quality error rates.
- Developed and integrated customized themes into WordPress, Joomla and Shopify.
- Support the QA team to design test cases for various change requests and enhancement.

Senior Front End Developer at NEXTBRIDGE (May 2014 – Oct 2017)

- Designed and implement a web app for storing the information of customer, generating sales reports, saving personal contacts and handling schedule management.
- Designed one-on-one with client to develop layout, color scheme and layout for his website and implemented it into a final interface design with HTML/CSS3&JavaScript.
- Developed page layouts, navigation and presented designs and concepts to the clients and the management to review
- Convert data from database into JSON or XML format files by the PHP file and retrieve useful information using AJAX calls to display them on the browser.
- Mentored and trained a team of 5 juniors to mid-level developers for front-end to WordPress development.

Skills:

PHP, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, WordPress CMS, Joomla CMS, Shopify

Language: English

Professional Qualification:

6 Months Diploma in Computer Graphics from National College of Arts, Lahore, Pakistan

Education:

Projects:

Designed and develop in Joomla(CMS) and Wordpress(CMS) all website is control through admin panel from where to change the content add pages and links and can also change theme.

https://theavantigroup.com.au/dev/

(Developed WordPress CMS by using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript an PHP)

https://shimmering-torte-e1c67a.netlify.app

(Developed chat app by using React JS with Chakra UI)

https://browcode.au/

(Developed Shopify Ecommerce Web by using HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Liquid Programming Ruby)

https://urbanbuz.com/

(WordPress CMS)

https://zeeshanazeem.com/

(WordPress CMS)

http://www.nahidsiddiqui.com/

(WordPress CMS)

http://saniyasce.global/

(WordPress CMS)

http://www.enrichcorporate.com/

(WordPress CMS)

http://bespokeglazingkent.com/

(WordPress CMS)

http://176.32.230.12/tajamal.com/nobelfoods/

(WordPress CMS)

https://www.pcma.org.pk/

(WordPress CMS)

http://www.sketchiz.com/

(WordPress CMS)

http://176.32.230.12/tajamal.com/archerwindowcleaning/

(WordPress CMS)

aestheticlife.com

(WordPress CMS)

asfp.org.uk

(WordPress CMS)

Lloyds-ss.co.uk

(WordPress CMS)

https://176.32.230.12/tajamal.com/paindoctor/

(WordPress CMS)

http://176.32.230.12/tajamal.com/bespoke/

(WordPress CMS)